okay so before we get going on
everything I have to talk about what it
means to have basic computer skills and
you think that this would be obvious but
I've learned over over time mentoring
one of people oneon-one that it's
actually not so I'm going to just
summarize these these individual items
in this kind of overview format right
now and then you can decide if you want
to drill down and get details about each
one of these bullet points so the first
one is you need to learn how to really
type I mean really type like touch type
um you need to get a computer that you
can modify that you have admin access to
I have taught so many classes where the
people that were in the class did not
have the ability to install software
because they weren't giving it to their
parents because they didn't trust their
kid install and learn the best web
browser what is the best web
browser stay tuned and check in for that
and we'll talk about what the best web
browser is for work specifically you
need to be able to create a free proton
mail account in my opinion if I were
mentoring you I would tell you you need
a protl account or you can't be with me
uh I have a separate video about why I
believe protl is the one true email
provider You can disagree with me and
that's fine but if you if I was
mentoring you I would require it uh you
need to have a Gmail account and a
Google and YouTube and all that uh
because you want to be able to use
YouTube but more importantly so you can
have multiple Gmail accounts that are
not being used for anything private
which can all go to the same place so
you can have multiple test accounts like
it for example and have them all mapped
to the same Gmail address which is then
forwarded to your centralized proton
account you need to have the ability to
set up a multiple Gmail accounts as I
mentioned which has got a video and then
you need to learn how to write notes you
need to be able to document your
learning that does not necessarily have
to be any particular way but we will
talk about markdown and HTML and yaml
and other methods for documenting your
learning but if you don't have the
ability specifically you need a GitHub
account you need a GitHub account you
need a private notes repo at the least
you probably need a lab repo also where
you can put your codeb book in a
codebook is a place where you put your
code that you write so that you create
your own textbook that you can go back
and refer to later as a way to practice
your skills this is all stuff that you
maintain that you own that you don't
have to ask permission to use you don't
have to subscribe you just have GitHub
right and You' have to have GitHub
period if you're going to be a
technologist today you need to develop
search sensoric user interface habits
you need to you need to know what alt
tab means you need to know how to use
the search Centric commands of your
system whether it's Mac or Windows or
Linux you need to get used to using that
because it will save you a tremendous
amount of time compared to digging down
through menus in you know whatever your
favorite um you know desktop interfaces
and it also completely negates the
argument about your desktop interface if
you don't have search Centric abilities
in your desktop interface then you're
doing it wrong in my opinion because
you're wasting time
unnecessarily um by learning whatever
their navigation system is um you need
to learn how to scan and read books
quickly whether it's a book or it's a
piece of technology we're going to uh um
you know like Kindle or something like
that or a web page uh later on Far later
on in the beginner boost we're going to
talk about using text-based web browsing
without a web browser so that you can
actually find things as fast as possible
and you will be able to scan and get
answers to your questions in seconds
that take people using graphic browsers
minutes and that I guarantee you if you
have not seen me do this this is the
number one thing people ask me how are
you doing this magic knowing how to do
text based research from the command
line is one of the most powerful things
you can learn to enable your ability to
get answers quickly which is a
fundamental skill in the in the in the
area of Technology um you'll learn to
use AI assistant like chat GPT from the
command line as fast as possible and
supplement your learning by doing that
um and getting answers from AI but
backing them up with answer hits that
come from Duck ducko and Google all done
from the command line these are all
basic computer skills um the the
searching from the command line is is
more advanced and we will talk about
that later but but knowing how to do
those searches um using a web browser
first um is sort of fundamental to being
able to say okay now let's do that same
thing but let's do it from the command
line and let's also have like a
commandline history of all of our
searches that we can query at any given
moment with Vim bindings for example
these are all uh I consider these to be
basic computer skills um you'll notice I
did not say that you need to be able to
install your own hardware and your own
operating system you will need to do
that but that's not basic and that will
be covered in uh the Linux module that
we talk about in the beginner boost so
that is meant this has been meant to be
an overview of the basic computer skills
and there will be videos you can drill
down on each of those